MOHAMED HMINI

 $+(44)7570159076 \Leftrightarrow Llandudno, UK$

mo@mhmini.com \$\dinkedin.com/mhmini \dinkedin.com

INTRODUCTION

Experienced MLOps Engineer with a 3-year background in Data Science, Data Engineering, and DevOps with degrees in Software Engineering and Intelligent Systems. I love problem solving and, most importantly, novelty when it comes to challenges, My cross-disciplinary skills help me to communicate effectively with colleagues from other disciplines. Actively seeking full-time MLOps positions.

EXPERIENCE

1. MLOps Engineer

Jan 2023 - Present Llandudno, UK

Viridien

• Productionising our ML System with packaging, containerization, CI/CD and K8s deployments.

- Actively optimizing our ML Pipeline to run efficiently on Azure as well as on-prem (e.g.: IO, CPU, GPU).
- A benchmarking driven redesign of our system for better scalability, transitioning from Spark to Argo workflows and then to a Producer/Consumer design, as well as supporting running Models in an Offline mode to avoid sending data over the network.
- Building, scaling, and optimizing an Azure Blob Storage events Consumer.
- MLOps, Building an end-to-end Model Deployment CI/CD template to be used to deploy all of our models to both Online and Offline modes.
- MLOps, building a tool to be used for Model Monitoring in production.
- Tools: Python, Spark, Argo, K8S, Docker, Gitlab CI/CD, Azure, Nuclio, Neo4j, Prometheus, Grafana, Mlflow, etc

2. Data Engineer

Viridien

Apr 2022 - Jan 2023

Llandudno, UK

- DevOps, coming up with adequate git branching strategies, helping with setting up CI/CD pipelines, dockerizing software.
- ML, modeling, building, testing and deploying machine learning models.
- Tools: Docker, Gitlab CI/CD, Python, Plotly Dash, Pytorch, etc

3. Data Engineer

EVEAD Group

Jan 2022 - Mar 2022

Casablanca, Morocco

- Building a google search based sitemap generator using selenium.
- Mimicking human behavior while browsing (dodging bot detections).
- Tools: Python, Selenium, Docker

4. Machine Learning Intern

LaBRI

Mar 2021 - Sep 2021 Bordeaux, France

- Synthesis and learning of boolean networks for predicting cellular differentiation.
- Creating Different Boolean Networks' Embedding techniques to allow for a multilevel view of the same Boolean Networks' ensemble.
- Applying Feature Selection techniques to isolate the good Boolean Networks.
- Resynthesize new Boolean Networks using the learned rules.
- Using Machine Learning to Optimize a rule-based symbolic A.i system.
- Contributing to BNeDiction code base.

EDUCATION

Master's Degree in Information Systems And Intelligent Systems (M2SI)	INSEA, Morocco	9/2019 - 9/2021
Bachelor's Degree in Information Systems And Big Data (BDSI)	ESTS, Morocco	9/2018 - 6/2019
DUT (Diplôme Universitaire de Technologie) Degree in Software Engineering	ESTM, Morocco	10/2016 - 6/2018

SOME EARLY PERSONAL PROJECTS

SKILLS

D-PandiSIM early 2021

Big data based pandemics distributed simulator, scoring network nodes using inverse PageRank.

Paysim Fraud Detection late 2020

Fraud detection using VAE and BNN networks, generating distributions of the output.

TweetsOLAPing early 2020

Implementing an end-to-end tweets ETL/Analysis pipeline.

IntelliWebWrapper early 2019

Intelligent web content extraction, extracting the main List Region (list of products).

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C, JavaScript, Prolog, Clingo, Lisp, SQL, etc

Programming Paradigms: Procedural, OOP, Functional, Distributed, Concurrent and Probabilistic

ML/Data Manipulation: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Sklearn, Pytorch, Pyro, Scrapy, SHAP, etc

Productionizing: Git versioning Strategies, Docker, Kubernetes (k8s), Helm, Gitlab CI/CD, Azure, Mlflow

Other Skills: Optimization techniques, Symbolic A.i, Statistics, Machine Learning, Explainable A.i, Game Theory, Web Crawling, NoSQL, etc

Other Tools: Pyspark, Nuclio, Mlrun, Triton, LabelStudio, Alibi-Detect, Neo4j, KubeRay, Argo Workflow, AirFlow etc

Languages: English, French, Arabic